What I'd like you to do is I'm going to go ahead and commit this code, and then you're going to practice creating a distor.
And so now we're going to migrate that over and see how far you can get.
And then I'll see you all on the other side.
I know for me, once I started using piny, like I was just so glad to not have to write mutations anymore,
and just just do the thing I want you to do, thank you and track it for me, like all that goodness.
Okay, so let me go ahead and make sure I push up the latest 10 exercise branch.
I think some people might not have gotten in. I didn't make.
So what I did do I guess for the purpose of record keeping is that if you check out the 10- exercise branch,
you'll notice that restaurant page has been properly like refactor to use all of the store.
So basically a couple things just to point out is that the number of restaurants I've actually restored,
because in this case we're doing the filtered restaurant list, and I haven't exactly moved that to the store just yet.
So this is a different type of number of restaurants versus the store number of restaurants,
which is like they call it the master copy of all the stores in perpetuity.
Okay, so with that, your job was to refactor the dishes page.
So let's go and do that. So creating a new store was the distor.ts,
and then we'll import defined store.
And then once we do that, we can export a cons called use distor,
and then define the store, and what's the idea going to be called?
We're going to call it distor.
And then we'll pass it in object for the state.
And so we know that the state is going to need some shape.
So let's go ahead and just define that now.
So we'll call that state shape.
And so for those wondering about like naming is a hard thing, right?
We talk a lot about that in programming,
but the one thing I like about keeping some of my states like types,
especially in line in my components or files,
is that I don't have to worry about it conflicting with something else.
Because obviously state shape is going to mean a lot of different things
across different components, but for this particular store,
state shape is just for this store.
So you don't have to worry about like, I'm going to call it distate state like store.
That's only relevant when you share it across multiple files,
but don't be afraid to inline your types directly on the file that it's working.
I'm a big fan of like I call it like data driven refactoring,
where you actually show that you have repeated code across pieces.
Then that's when you take the time to actually modularize it,
start extracting refactoring.
So that said, we do know for a fact that we'll have a list similarly,
and we'll have a dish that will be in a race.
So that's basically all we need to know.
So there's my list, and then I can grab all of this stuff here.
Pump-up-up-up-up-up.
Oh my gosh, it's not scrolling the way I wanted to.
All right, doing it manually.
Great cut.
Then we can now define that here.
Great, that looks good.
Then filter list or a dish list.
As we say, dish list equals use, dish store.
Like that.
Although I realized the dish store should actually be dish store first,
and we'll use that.
And then we'll say dish store.list.
Just for like helping things clean up a little bit.
There we go.
Dish list.filter.
Does not exist on property ref dish.
Oh, there's a duplicate reference.
That's why.
Dish dish dish dish.
And then dish list.
That's fine.
The only thing though that's kind of interesting is that it is saying that
dish does not match dish.
This is an interesting overload.
Okay.
Why is it yelling at me?
Oh, well, that makes sense.
I never actually defined the state shape.
I defined it up here.
Did not use it.
So now that I've saved it, now this error goes away.
Again, so what's nice is that as you sprinkle in TypeScript,
it shows you the errors that makes sense as you go, right?
And so as we can see here, it's not overly intrusive.
And it's overall throughout this research.
You've seen it multiple times.
Catch me in an error where I might have just moved on and just be like,
hey, something's funky here.
You might have less something off.
And that is really valuable for us as developers.
So let's keep going.
Number of dishes.
We're going to keep this the same because as I mentioned earlier,
this is actually contingent on a filter text.
That's happening.
And so we're going to leave that alone.
We're not going to worry about that.
But all this stuff, these are actions that we can take.
So let's actually, yes, I can take this.
So these actions are going to get defined here.
Actions, boom.
And then we'll take that.
And then once again, actions should be just like normal functions,
not error functions because we're going to need to access the entire store.
And then from here, we can basically say state.this.list.plush the payload.
This.plush.
That's good.
That's not necessary right now.
Then we can say this.list is equal to this.list.filter.
That filters everything.
That'll go ahead and filter everything.
So now, when we come to refactor this,
we still need this high-formed functionality.
So it's for that reason that we'll go ahead and just do this store.addish.
We'll be dropping the payload.
However, for delete dish, one of the things that we don't,
this is basically identical.
So really, we don't need to actually even create a function here.
We'll be can do it inside of where delete dish exists.
We'll just call it dishstore.lead-dish.
And one of the things I really like about this sort of modular declaration of store,
because some people will be like, well, I want to destructure it.
And I want to make it trimmer.
But the fact that you know immediately online 31,
this is coming from a global store, that is incredibly valuable.
I think for debugging, especially as we know, as code bases get more complex,
the likelihood for name clashing and that kind of stuff happens.
So to me, just being a little bit more declarative,
but knowing instantly what it is,
comprehension is huge when it comes to code maintainability.
So personally, huge fan of this.
Okay, that's that, that's that.
I think that's it.
So now we have everything in here, dishless.
Yeah, just store.
This is great.